[Coroner's Diary]
[Episode 21]
Master,
Prince Cheng's men are
still outside.
Prince Cheng
apparently came here for Mr. Qin.
Now, the victims' clothes are
mysteriously missing.
I'm worried that...
Capital Prefect,
Young Master Qin is an strategist of mine.
Please address her
as Master Wan from now on.
Yes, I got it.
-But now…
-Don’t worry.
I only need four hours as I said.
To proceed,
I'll have to trouble Constable Zhan
for one thing.
I'm at Your Highness's service.
Please go to the East Water Gate
and identify the fish vendors
who deliver fish to the restaurants
in the West Market.
Got it.
Didn't Master Wan say
the victim must've eaten in a small diner?
Why would fish vendors
bother to make deliveries to small diners?
Fish are fragile goods.
Some are inevitably damaged
during transport.
Fish vendors
usually keep the dead and injured fish
for themselves,
or sell them cheaply to small diners.
Finding the right fish vendor
will lead us to the diner
that purchased the fish.
I understand now.
But Prince Cheng...
Master Wan is new to the city.
I'll show her around first.
It'll only take two hours.
Bai Feng,
be our coachman.
Yes.
Two hours...
The Marquis of Zhongyong is
sparing no effort
to assist the Crown Prince.
I can't believe he'd drag you into this.
I was looking for a chance
to enter the criminal justice system.
What they've done suits me perfectly,
and has saved you much trouble.
I don't mind trouble.
It's just that there's a tangled net of
power players behind this matter.
I'm afraid the attention you get
will endanger you.
Today, you've seen
the way Prince Cheng acts.
You should be aware of
the uncontainable hostility
between him and the Crown Prince
You might be
caught in their political struggles
and reduced to a pawn of others'.
I'm not afraid.
Don't worry.
I'll be cautious.
To seek justice for the murdered women
and to clear
Prince Jin's and my father's names,
I must pursue
this case to the end.
Okay.
Go ahead and act as you see fit.
Just don't forget to keep your guard up.
The Emperor has granted me
approval today.
From now on, you can work on any cases
undertaken by the Ministry of Justice.
Thank you.
[Prince Yi’s Mansion]
Why did you bring me
to Prince Yi's residence?
I want you to meet someone.
It's also a way to lose those tails.
It seems desolate. How come?
It's a prince's mansion without a prince.
How can it not appear desolate?
Chi.
Why are you here so early?
Fix your clothes.
Where did you hang out last night?
Little Wan'er?
Chi, why didn't you tell me
she was coming too?
She might be charmed by my pretty looks.
You can't blame me if that happens.
Your Highness is worrying about nothing.
You're dressed like a man
shortly after your return to the capital.
Is it because you find
men's apparel classy,
or because you're
investigating a case again?
There's a spy for Yan Qi at the gate.
Go chase him away.
Why are Prince Cheng's people after you?
You're not working on that tricky case
for the Crown Prince, are you?
Cut the crap. Go get rid of that spy now.
I'll wait till you come back
to visit Madam.
You go visit her alone.
She'd rather read scriptures than see me.
She'd only make an exception for you.
I'll go deal with
that hateful spy.
Your clothes!
I've brought a friend to meet Madam.
Is she available now?
Madam is copying scriptures.
Please wait a moment.
Why do you all refer to
Yan Li's mother as "Madam"
instead of "Princess"?
I'll tell you later.
Just call her "Madam."
[Princess Yi]
Greetings, Madam.
I haven't seen you for over a year.
Now, you're looking
more and more like your father.
Who is this?
She's Qin Wan,
the ninth child of the Qin family.
Her father is Qin Liang.
Nice to meet you, Madam.
I didn't know about your visit,
so I didn't prepare any gifts.
I came here without notice.
Apologies for my rudeness.
This is not much of a gift,
but I'd like you to have it.
I can't accept it.
Chi
has finally brought a lady to meet me.
I'm very delighted.
Please take it.
Maybe it'll remind you of me
in the future.
Thank you, Madam.
During our stay in the capital,
we'll pay regular visits to you.
No need.
Just look after Li for me.
Chi,
if possible,
leave the capital soon.
I guess this hairpin
symbolizes the love
between Madam and Prince Yi.
Why did she give it to me,
instead of saving it for Yan Li?
Do you know about
the rebellion staged by Fu Chengye
20 years ago,
the then
Sichuan pacification commissioner?
The Fu family were all executed
for that reason.
Madam is Fu Chengye's younger sister.
Then Prince Yi...
Prince Yi
reported to Fu Chengye.
He was the inspector-general of Gongzhou,
named Yan Han.
Prince Yi was a farmer's son
who later enlisted with military forces.
Given his brilliant track records,
Fu Chengye valued him
and married his own daughter to him.
[Tier-one loyal warrior]
[Fu Residence]
When Prince Yi discovered
Fu Chengye's intent to start a coup,
Madam was already pregnant with Yan Li.
So, while pretending to escort Madam
to her hometown before labor,
he was secretly rushing to the capital
to deliver the message.
Later, he was informed
that the Imperial Guards
led by the Crown Prince
had been ambushed at the Storm Ridge.
That was the current Emperor's first time
to command a troop as the Crown Prince.
By the time he realized it was a trap,
he had been surrounded
by arrows dipped in tung oil.
Prince Yi hurried to the Storm Ridge
overnight
and single-handedly rescued
the Emperor from raging flames.
Regrettably,
the reinforcements arrived
only to find Prince Yi had been burned
beyond recognition.
Yet until his dying breath,
he had been guarding in front of
the severely injured Emperor.
The Emperor was deeply moved
by Yan Han's loyalty.
After ascending the throne,
His Majesty overruled all objections
and honored Yan as "Prince Yi"
in memory of his allegiance.
The Emperor also took Yan Li in
as his godson
and bestowed upon him
the imperial surname,
"Yan."
So, Yan Li is just
an honorary heir of a prince.
None of the capital's bigwigs
truly consider him
as part of the royal family.
Why wasn't Madam granted
the title of princess?
Mrs. Yan meant to join Yan Han in death,
but she couldn't bear the thought of
Yan Li becoming parentless at a young age.
After declining rewards and honors,
she started living in seclusion.
Fortunately, Grandmother
treats Yan Li like her own grandson.
As long as Grandmother lives,
nobody in the palace
would dare to openly disrespect him.
A lifelong commitment...
Madam and Prince Yi
really loved each other dearly.
I suppose this wooden hairpin contains
Madam's wish for us to be
a loving couple forever.
But if misfortunes befall you,
I'll definitely not join you in death.
I'll search every corner on earth
to hunt down
those who harmed you.
Your words...
have really put my mind...
at ease.
You can rest assured.
Even if you die,
I'll carry on with my life.
I'm assured.
You can rest assured too.
By no means I'll die before you do.
Master!
[Capital Prefecture]
I misled
those spies
to the Maquis of Zhongyong's mansion.
Have the Dove Unit
take them for a tour around the capital,
so they can't get in our way.
Got it.
Your Highness,
Master Wan,
I have a small finding now.
The capital prefect has been waiting.
Please lead the way, Constable Zhang.
No intimate contact here.
I won't share a carriage with you anymore.
Not here?
Then anywhere else is fine?
Thank you for coming.
I was just wondering
where the perpetrator captured
these three victims,
since there is zero connection
among these girls,
and their workplaces are far from
where their bodies were dumped.
No need to rush, Capital Prefect.
Constable Zhan, can you
get us some red strings,
red pens
and pins?
Sure.
What does Your Highness need those for?
The murderer hasn't left a trail.
It means this person acts
with extreme caution and prudence.
People of this kind
usually commit crimes in familiar places
and premeditate the timing
and routes.
This perpetrator kills every half a month.
If he ran a tailor shop independently,
he wouldn't have the time
to look around for preys in the capital.
If his shop were frequently closed,
it would surely arouse suspicion.
So,
the three places
where he dumped the bodies
can tell us the possible murder site.
But these places
aren't close to one another.
Your Highness.
Constable Zhan,
please put these pins
onto the map,
where the murderer disposed of the bodies.
The first victim
was found under Yushui Bridge.
The second victim
was left in an abandoned house.
The third one
was discovered in an alley.
Red strings.
The curfew starts at 11 p.m.,
and is lifted at 3 a.m..
To avoid being spotted,
the murderer had to discard the bodies
and return home
within this period of time.
Besides, he couldn't use trolleys
or horses to transport the bodies.
It is hard for an average-sized adult man
to walk four to five li within two hours
while carrying a body
weighing about 50 kilograms.
Plus the time spent in resting,
hiding from patrols
and dealing with the bodies,
it would take at least three hours.
The rest of the time would be just enough
for him to go home
and prepare to open the shop.
This area is
no more than five li away
from each dump site.
Bai Feng,
take some people with you
and look for the shops
with stairways.
The murderer could be a tailor,
and his shop
might be rented.
I got it.
Don't just check the shops.
As His Highness said,
the perpetrator is meticulous.
He probably has
a different hideout in this area.
Make sure you check
every house with stairways.
Yes.
Bai Feng.
In just a few hours,
we'll hit the deadline.
Take this token with you.
Ignore today's curfew.
Set out now.
Your Highness,
I have found some diners
that sell fish porridge
in the West Market.
I'll go with you to the West Market
to interview the fish vendors.
Okay.
I want to go to the morgue
to see if I can find new clues
from the bodies.
I will accompany Master Wan.
Don't worry, Your Highness.
If anything happens,
remember to use the Red Flare.
I'm just a lowly prostitute.
How am I able to afford your education?
Why do you have to be a boy?
Why are you a boy?
Tell me.
Why can't you be a girl?
Why...
Why aren't you a girl?
If you were a girl,
I could pimp you out
for money.
Why do you have to be a boy?
Why?
Get me more liquor.
Your Highness,
there is a message
from the Marquis of Zhongyong.
The coroner I recommended
has found some clues.
Chi is
hunting for the suspect.
What else did the marquis say?
His Grace
told Your Highness not to worry.
Good.
If this case can be solved on time,
the Marquis of Zhongyong
will surely be rewarded.
[Morgue]
Capital Prefect.
Mr. Fang.
Where are the three victims' bodies?
Their bodies?
Capital Prefect, didn't you just order
the bodies to be taken away?
I never gave that order.
What about the victims' clothes?
Taken away too, of course.
I was truly baffled.
It's freezing cold now.
The bodies could've been buried
after the case is closed.
Do you know who took the bodies away?
I certainly do.
That was the officer
who brought the bodies over
last time with Constable Zhan.
It's Prince Cheng's doing again.
How could this happen?
He took all the evidence away.
How are we supposed to solve the case?
Let's go back to the prefect's office.
His Highness will
definitely find new evidence.
Gentlemen,
you came early.
The cooking has just started.
In the West Market,
our fish porridge
has the most authentic local flavor.
Serve some side dishes first.
We'd like to taste
your famous local-flavored porridge.
Alright, just a moment.
Your Highness, do you think
this is where the third victim
last ate?
The third victim
lived outside the city.
She rarely came in town for procurements.
I bet she'd love to taste
the most authentic
local-flavored fish porridge.
Food's coming!
Mister,
look at this sachet of yours.
Are you getting married soon?
You're mistaken, sir.
This sachet isn't mine.
Previously, a young lady
came for porridge
and left it behind.
Well,
I thought she'd come back for it,
so I hung it on my waist
for it to be easily noticed.
Do you remember
what that young lady was wearing?
She was in...
ordinary ko-hemp, as I recall.
Your Highness,
the third victim
was exactly wearing ko-hemp clothes.
I-Is that young lady dead?
Then...
this sachet...
How...
should I...
This is a contract about the making of
a wedding dress.
The pickup date is precisely
the day of the victim's missing.
Shopkeeper!
Sir.
Sit down, miss.
Have some tea.
Take a rest.
Thank you.
There are only a few stitches to make.
The dress will be finished soon.
Thank you, sir.
How kind of you.
It's Jinyi Shop!
Bai Feng,
follow the map to find Jinyi Shop.
Catch the murderer.
All the physical evidence
has gone missing now,
so we must secure the testimonies.
Yes!
Capital Prefect,
we may arrest the murderer in time,
but without physical evidence,
Prince Cheng can still make false claims.
What is there to do then?
I suggest you write a memorial
to condemn yourself.
It's time for Master Wan to leave
and prepare to attend the royal banquet.
I'll write the memorial right away.
Master Wan,
I deeply appreciate your help.
Now, you need to think about
tonight's royal banquet.
Isn't it time for the Emperor
to meet the talent I hired?
Do I really have to go?
The Marquis of Zhongyong
would definitely make Qin Wan go.
[Capital Prefecture]
I'm not going.
It's the annual New Year's
royal gathering.
You've been absent from it every year.
This is a family reunion.
How could you not join us?
Which of those people is my family?
I didn't share the same surname with them
until 20 years ago.
I'd hate to be an eyesore.
I'd better spare them
from the awkwardness of seeing me,
an outsider.
How are you an outsider?
I'm leaving now.
You...
Tomorrow morning,
I'll pay a New Year's visit to Madam.
Okay!
I'll be waiting for you.
What are you doing here?
Chi specially asked me
to prepare clothes and jewelry for you.
I also need to
instruct you on court etiquette
and codes of conduct.
You have no idea
how calculating and cunning
the capital's noble ladies are.
How can I send you to the lion's den
without giving you some tips first?
What do I have to fear?
I'll just pretend not to
understand anything,
being all quiet and still.
Those cunning ladies
can't do anything to me.
Impressive. What a smart strategy—
playing dumb.
Ning,
I have only one reminder for you.
During the royal banquet,
I'll be visiting the Empress Dowager
in Funing Palace.
If anyone bullies you two,
don't hesitate to fight back.
The blood of resistance
flows in our family.
Everyone knows about
Grandmother's hot temper.
Chi,
you should be telling me
not to strike too hard instead.
Chi,
why didn't you ask Little Wan'er
what she fed you before eating it?
Wan offered it to me.
Did I even need to ask?
This pill helps him stay sober.
He can have a lot of drinks
without getting drunk.
I want one too.
Why are you born a woman,
but I'm not?
You're merely the daughter of
the Duke of Zhong.
[Yan Zhen]
[A royal princess]
How dare you sit next to me.
Who do you think you are?
[Feng Chenbi]
Maids,
get her a new seat.
The Emperor designated
Noble Consort Su to organize this banquet.
His Majesty allowed me
to sit in this very place.
Your Highness had better
mind your manners.
Otherwise,
you'll be a disgrace to the Empress.
The girl in the left front seat
is Princess Yan Zhen,
the Empress's daughter.
The girl next to her
is Feng Chenbi,
whose father, the Duke of Zhong, is
Noble Consort Su's confidant.
These two girls
are arch nemeses.
But whenever Qin Zhaoyu shows up,
they two will immediately become allies.
Is Feng Chenbi
also into the Crown Prince?
Not all the rivalries among noble ladies
throughout history are about men, right?
This banquet was organized
by Noble Consort Su.
The Empress didn't take part in it at all.
So, you can see
who's having an edge now.
Royal concubines fight one another
with all means
only for their children's sake.
A favored mother's son enjoys more power.
That's why Prince Cheng always has
the upper hand over the Crown Prince.
It is also why the Qin family
is facing many obstacles
in its every attempt
to marry a daughter into the royal family.
A boisterous occasion, isn't it?
Yes, indeed.
Your aunt
should've been seated at the back.
But the Empress likes Qin Zhaoyu a lot,
so your aunt could get a seat
in the middle row.
Speaking of which,
given your help to the Crown Prince
this time,
the Empress might treat you differently.
If that happens...
The Emperor arrives!
[Zhao Shuhua]
[Empress]
[Feng Lingsu]
[Noble Consort Su]
Greetings, Your Majesty!
The Empress Dowager
is feeling slightly unwell.
I'll keep you company on her behalf.
Everyone,
just make yourself at home.
Thank Your Majesty.
Rise.
Ning,
is the lady beside you
the Grand Princess's
god-granddaughter?
Yes, Your Majesty,
she is.
I'm Qin Wan. Greetings, Your Majesty.
I wish Your Majesty
longevity and wellness.
Forgo the formalities.
Thank Your Majesty.
The Grand Princess
has told me what you did
in Jingzhou.
In the letter,
she particularly asked me
to take good care of
her dear
Wan.
If not,
she'll come to the capital with her whip.
I am
very much frightened.
Rest assured, Your Majesty.
I promise I'll take good care of myself
and not worry the Grand Princess.
Don't concern about me, Your Majesty.
The prescription I made
for the Grand Princess
is nerve-soothing.
Her Highness
hasn't raised her whip for a long time.
Are Miss Qin's medical skills
really good enough
to change
a person's temperament?
Your Majesty,
I'm an eyewitness
to Wan's medical competence.
In Jingzhou,
people all refer to her
as a medical fairy.
What a surprise
that the Marquis of Zhongyong
has a medical fairy as his daughter.
He is a blessed father.
That's a much higher honor
than the hollow title of
the capital's most talented woman.
Women excel in different fields.
Why compare them with one another?
Be they good at arts, medicine,
needlework, cooking or anything,
they deserve respect and admiration
as long as they are
sensible women of integrity.
Well said.
I can't agree more with
Miss Qin's opinion.
Return to your seats, ladies.
Thank Your Majesty.
Why are you still out here?
Are you waiting for me?
Or are you afraid
that Father will ask you
about those women's murders?
Had I known you cared
so much about this case,
I would've asked Father
to let you handle it.
You are the Crown Prince
who protects the capital,
while I'm just the inferior Prince Cheng.
How could I compare myself
with Your Highness?
Crown Prince,
Prince Cheng,
the officials
are waiting outside now.
Announce our presence.
Yes.
[Chongming Palace]
Happy New Year, Father.
May Your Majesty be well in the new year.
You may all rise.
-Thank you, Father.
-Thank Your Majesty.
Be seated.
Come on, everyone.
Drink
this up.
I wish you wellness in the new year.
We wish Your Majesty wellness
in the new year.
The Heir of Prince Rui is requesting
an audience with Your Majesty.
Chi has arrived.
Let him in now!
Your Majesty,
I wish you longevity and wellness.
Happy New Year.
Forgo the formalities.
Thank Your Majesty.
Come on,
give Chi
a bigger glass.
Fill it up to make up for the drink
he missed.
Your Highness, here you are.
You're just like your father.
Yuan Qing,
give him a refill.
Yes.
Watching Chi drink
is such a delight
for me.
Bravo!
Your Majesty,
though this is a family gathering,
I still have to make a report.
Mr. Song,
what do you have to report?
Your Majesty,
on this New Year's Eve,
while the people are celebrating,
I can't help but
think of those brutally murdered girls
and their families.
It really unsettles me.
How can they spend
this joyous occasion happily
with grief and anger
weighing on their hearts?
The time limit has been reached.
Crown Prince, please give updates
on the investigation of this case,
so as to ease the people's minds.
Father,
significant progress has been made
for this case.
It will be solved very soon.
What progress?
I...
I
have a report to present.
I'll allow it.
Your Majesty,
the case about the murdered girls
was just solved today.
The Crown Prince was reluctant
to bring it up in the royal banquet
on the New Year's Eve,
so I didn't dare to present the report.
This memorial was written
by the capital prefect
to state the conclusion of this case.
Please read it, Your Majesty.
The cold-blooded and brutal murderer
failed to take another girl's life,
thanks to the timely arrival of
Constable Zhan
from the capital prefecture.
This tailor
committed gruesome murders
out of jealousy of
women marrying up.
How astounding it is
to uncover
such a vicious murderer
in my reign!
Your Majesty,
this person
was traumatized from being abused
in childhood by his mother.
This brutal killer deserves no sympathy.
It has to be made clear
that his motive was purely personal
and unrelated to Your Majesty's reign.
The fact that this bizarre murder case
could be solved within several days
exactly proves
Your Majesty's administration
effective and reliable.
Good.
Rise and talk.
-Thank you, Father.
-Thank Your Majesty.
The Crown Prince and the capital prefect
have both done a good job.
Besides, I've noticed
from the capital prefect's memorial
that some obvious clues
were revealed
by
the coroner.
How come this talent
hadn't made
any notable achievements before?
Your Majesty,
this coroner
was recently recommended
by the Crown Prince's royal guardian—
Qin Shu,
the Marquis of Zhongyong.
Your Majesty,
for the wellbeing of the country,
I'd gladly do anything
within my capacity.
Mr. Qin,
I appreciate it.
Your Majesty,
there is
a memorial asking for punishment
awaiting your review.
The capital prefect
admits that he failed to
keep the evidence safe
and is now asking for punishment.
This...
The victims' clothes went missing.
Their bodies were destroyed.
I can't believe
the capital prefecture would make
such a huge mistake right under my nose!
I vouch for the capital prefect.
Every word in the memorial
is absolutely true.
In that case,
I'll assign you
to arrest those
who destroyed the evidence
and obstructed the official investigation
immediately.
Yes,
as Your Majesty commands.
Crown Prince,
you dealt with this matter properly
and meticulously.
As we are
celebrating the New Year,
maintaining
the peace and prosperity of the country is
indeed our priority.
Thank you for your praise, Father.
Alright.
Be seated then, everyone.
-Thank you, Father.
-Thank Your Majesty.
Come on,
raise your glasses.
Let us
toast to
a prosperous new year.
May Your Majesty be well in the new year.
[Empress Dowager]
Your Majesty!
Are you feeling unwell, Your Highness?
All this coughing is making my chest ache.
Shall I ask for a royal physician?
No need.
It happens every year.
This is the New Year's Eve.
I'd hate to disturb the Emperor.
My chest feels very tight.
Help me step out for some fresh air.
Yes.
Slowly.
Your Majesty?
Your Majesty!
Help!
Get the royal physicians here!
Go to Chongming Palace
to inform the Emperor now!
Yes.
Your Majesty?
Let the evil-repelling ritual commence!
The player of that general
must be from the Imperial Guards.
He has excellent martial skills.
Indeed.
Very good.
I, Yan Chi,
wish Your Majesty
a lifetime of wellness!
He...
He's Chi, isn't he?
In the blink of an eye,
how did you go from a real general
to a fake one?
Your Majesty,
the people will benefit from
your wisdom.
I stand ready to repel all evil
for Your Majesty,
as it is also my duty.
Good.
I'd love to hear that!
Now,
you're the vice minister of
the Ministry of Justice.
You shall
safeguard the country's peace for me.
Thank Your Majesty!
Alright.
You may rise.
Thank Your Majesty.
How
considerate of Chi.
Now that the ritual is over,
Empress,
let's go to
Zhenghua Gate
to celebrate this occasion
with all the commoners.
Yes, as Your Majesty commands.
Good.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty,
the Empress Dowager...
is in critical condition!
How come?
Her Majesty suddenly fell ill.
Then...
why didn't she ask for a royal physician?
All the royal physicians are
in Funing Palace now.
The problem is,
Her Majesty can't ingest any medical soup.
Her Majesty is lingering
between life and death!
Prepare my carriage!
Little Wan'er,
please go check on the Empress Dowager.
She treats me nicely.
The situation is unclear now.
Any rash decisions could
turn us into someone else's pawns.
Don't worry. If possible,
I'll definitely help her.
Okay.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
this is the beginning of a new year.
If the people
can't see the Emperor, the Empress
and the Crown Prince,
I'm afraid they'll be thrown into panic.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty, the country's wellness
comes before anything!